What's wrong?
どうしたの？　出てきて！
Come on out!
You gotta go!
Don't let this opportunity slip by!
行くしかねえだろ　好機を逃すな！
To think I'd be in such a situation!
まさか　こんなことになろうとは
華やかさとは　無縁のわが人生がここへきて
My life, led lacking all splendor, is heading
toward a climax surrounded by three women!
女性３人に囲まれるという　最高潮を迎えている
But!
しかし！
Unless I am to become some Renaissance man of the sexual arts, I must decide on one of them!
八面六臂の桃色遊戯の達人を　目指す
器でないならば
一人に決めなくてはならない
And obviously that's the one with the real body, right?
もちろん　生身の体だろ！
Come on out!
出てきて！
羽貫さんは　心情的にも　ビジュアル的にも
申し分ない女性だが
Hanuki-san is a woman with no faults on an emotional or visual level,
こよいの彼女は　あまりにも…
but tonight she was just too...
Quit it with the pretentious monologues already!
しちめんどくさい　ご託　並べるな！
Let your feelings guide your body!
感情に身を任せろ！
Carry me away...
わたしを　さらって
Kaori-san is a silent, lovely maiden.
香織さんは　無口で　かれんな乙女　しかし
However, we are fated to be apart!
彼女とわたしは　結ばれぬ運命
分かる　分かるけどよ
I know! I know already, sheesh!
If we are not able to meet, then I cannot continue this relationship any longer.
「会えなければ　これ以上
関係を　続けることはできません」
景子さんは　古風で　しとやかな女性
Keiko-san is classy and ladylike,
but I can't see her like that!
しかし　わたしは　彼女においそれと　会えない
それも　なしじゃねえけど
この状況なら　答えは一つだろ！
That's true, sure...
In this situation there's only one choice, right?
Therefore...
ならば！
ならばー！
Therefore!
hitobito wa atsui kumo ni kao wo kakushiteru
人々は厚い雲で顔を隠してる
Humans hide their faces in front of thick clouds
iki ba no nai omoi wo zutto motte toideiru
行き場のない想いをずっと持って研いでいる
Getting more and more consumed by the feeling of getting nowhere
nani mo nai machi ni umorete mo sore demo ima demo
何もない街に埋もれても それでも 今でも
Even now, they're still buried in the same empty town
tsuranaru uindou ni
連なるウィンドウに
A perfect dream of dolls lined up
narabitatsu ningyou no marui yume
並び立つ人形の悪い夢
on a stretched out window
sore to mo soko ni kakurete
それとも倉庫に隠れて
Then they hide themselves away
fusaidetatte
塞いでたって
so that they can be covered up
hokori dake kabutte mitsukaranai
埃だけ被って見つからない
Wearing only their pride, they still can't find anything
dare no te ni datte furerarenai
誰の手にだって触れられない
They still aren't touched, no matter whose hands they're in
boku tachi no genzai wo kurikaesu koto darake demo
僕たちの現在を繰り返すことだらけでも
If we repeat this moment of ours properly,
sou itsuka kimi to deaou
そういつか君と出会おう
I will meet you someday
sonna hi wo omotte hibi wo ikou
そんな日を思って 日々を行こう
Until that day is here, I will keep on going
ikou
行こう
Going
Then I was a brand-spanking new freshman university student
当時　ぴかぴかの　大学１回生だった
わたしの前には
and before my eyes were open innumerable doors to that rose-colored campus life.
ばら色の　キャンパスライフへの扉が
無数に　開かれていた
しかし　一つのサークルに　身を捧げるということは
However, devoting my life to a single circle
poses a chance of wasting my entire college life in vain.
ともすれば　大学生活を丸ごと
棒に振るということにも　なりかねない
リスクは分散すべし
One must spread out the risk!
複数のサークルに参加して　多角的な
ばら色の　キャンパスライフを送るのだ！
I will join many circles and experience a diversified rose-colored campus life!
"English Conversation Circle"
"Korea"
"Sea of Japan"
"Tottori Sand Dunes"
"Lake Biwa"
"Kyoto Prefecture"
I bet I could take trips abroad as easily as going to Awaji Island.
淡路島に行くように　気軽に
海外へも　足を伸ばせるだろう
"Awaji Island"
"Jupiter"
"Russia"
"Mars"
"Japan"
"Kibo"
Able to read English newspapers,
英字新聞も読めるし　日本語だけの
偏った情報に　踊らされることもない
I would no longer be forced to dance only to Japanese language news.
言語は　数多くあれど
Among the large number of native languages, it's the one spoken by most people.
最も多くの人が　話す言葉「イングリッシュ」
English!
誰とでも会話ができる　外国人と知り合いになれる
Able to converse with anyone...
Able to make acquaintances with foreigners...
"Self Pride"
"Sense of Shame"
And most of all, not encumbered by Japanese's arrogant sense of shame or enlarged self-pride,
何より　日本語では　尊大な羞恥心と
肥大した自尊心が　邪魔をしてならないが
with English conversation I can have a buoyant talk session with a raven-haired maiden.
英会話でなら　黒髪の乙女とも　弾むような
トークセッションができる
身に付けておいて　損はない
There's no down-side to learning that skill!
This is difficult... Conversing in English like this is a tough road to travel.
苦しい
こんなにも　英会話というものが　険しい道だったとは
Ｗｈａｔ　ｄｏ　ｙｏｕ　ｌｉｋｅ　ｔｏ　ｄｏ？
Here we go again...
まただ
頭の中で　文法を　整理し
推敲に推敲を　重ねてるうちに
As I put the grammar together in my head,
improving and polishing the thought,
会話は　早くも次のステージに　いってしまうのだ
the conversation has already proceeded to the next stage.
Damn, I'm taking this way too seriously.
ああ　きまじめさが邪魔をする
However, if the other choice is spouting some grammatically incorrect English,
しかし　文法的に破綻した英文を口にするくらいなら
I will take pride in being a man of few words!
わたしは　栄光ある科目を選ぶ
Silent as usual, I see.
相変わらず　無口ね
If you don't say anything, it's your loss.
しゃべらないと　損するだけよ？
I have plenty of English vocabulary in my head, but...
頭の中は英単語で　いっぱいなのですが…
You should just go with your feelings.
もっと　気持ちに　身を任せればいいのに
Hanuki-san's English was left a bit too much to her feelings,
羽貫さんの英語は　気持ちに
身を任せ過ぎであったが
ちゃんと　先生に伝わっているのは　奇怪であった
and to be honest, it's a miracle the
instructor understood a thing she said.
わたしごときが　模倣できるものではない
ソウルトークである
It was speaking from the soul which I myself could never hope to do.
"Dental Hygienist License
Name: Hanuki Ryouko"
Hanuki-san is a dental hygienist,
羽貫さんは　歯科衛生士であり
職場で起こった　出来事を　歯の知識を　織り交ぜながら
and she spoke passionately about her work and knowledge of teeth,
感情豊かに話すので
サークル内の　デンタルＩＱは　跳ね上がっていった
raising everyone in the circle's dental IQ.
And among her talks, the badmouthing of "Sexual Harassment Dentist Kubouzuka"
"Sexual Harassment Dentist Kubouzuka Part 15"
中でも　「セクハラ医師の窪塚」の悪口は
みんなから　喝采の的であった
was most acclaimed.
タッチ　マイボディー　ノー　ノー　ノー　バチーン！
くるくる　バターン
ノック　アウト！
ヘイトー　クボヅカ
She and I had a common acquaintance.
彼女とわたしには　共通の知り合いがいた
へえー　小津君　同回生なんだ　スモールワールドね
Oh, so you and Ozu-kun are in the same year?
It's a small world, you know?
彼　わたしが勤めてる歯医者の　クランケさんなのよ
He's a patient at our practice.
治りかけたと思ったら　いつも　来なくなるんだから
Every time I think he's about to be fixed up,
he reverts back, so he never completely heals.
いつまでたっても　完治しないの
I suspect it is just a plot by him to keep tasting your fingers, Hanuki-san.
おおかた　羽貫さんの指の味を
しゃぶり続けようって　魂胆です
あいつは　そういう悪知恵を　すぐ　思い付く
He's always thinking up cunning plots like that.
That's his hobby.
それが　趣味だもんね
人の生活に　いらんちょっかいを出すのが
生きがいのやつです
He lives for messing with other people's lives.
Ozu and I are in the same year.
小津は　わたしと同回生である
Despite being in the electrical engineering department,
工学部で　電気電子工学科にも
所属するにもかかわらず
電気も　電子も　工学も嫌いである
he hates both electricity and electronics, as well as engineering.
出会ったのは　１回生の６月であった
I first met him in June of our freshman year.
Sir, might you be troubled?
だんな　お困りでないすか？
Who the hell are you?
誰だ　貴様！　魂の契約をしに来た　悪魔か！
Are you a devil who wants to bargain away my soul?
ひどいこと　おっしゃる
You say some pretty mean things.
わたしは　あなたのサポートを　したいんです
I want to support you!
College life is super-busy with searching for love.
大学生活は　恋に遊びに大忙し
そんな　皆さまの勉学の負担を　少しでも　減らそうと
If it might help to lower the burden of your academic study,
手前ども　あらゆるリポートも　ご用意しております
we have prepared reports for most occasions...
Please, make use of them to fully experience this abundant campus life.
ぜひ　実りある　キャンパスライフのために　ご活用ください
Right now, we're holding a sale.
今なら　お安くできますよ
I, juggling three clubs at once,
and pressured by school work,
３つのサークルを　掛け持ち
学業を　おろそかにしていた　わたしは
was easily cajoled by Ozu's wheedling.
小津の口車に　つい　乗せられてしまった
The organization known as the
"Print Shop" creates forged reports,
印刷所という　その組織は　偽造リポートを　製造しており
and I had fallen into a situation where I was dependent on them to get me out of jams.
今では　わたしは　印刷所の助けを　借りなければ
急場をしのげない体に　なってしまっていた
Hence, my inability to break off my relationship with him I so despised.
小津との腐れ縁を断ち切り難い　原因は　ここにある
Ozu is nothing but trouble.
小津には　迷惑　掛けられっ放しですからね
あいつは　ほかにも　いろんなサークルで
暗躍しているらしいんです
It sounds like he has underhanded dealings in a bunch of other circles.
He won't rest unless discord is ringing out from all around him.
常に　周りで　不協和音が
響いてないと　落ち着かない
あいつがいなければ　わたしも
もっと　ましな人生を　歩んでいたはずです
I'm sure that if he wasn't here, I would have led a better life.
Man, he pisses me off...
くそっ　いまいましい！
If you're so worked up about it, why don't you talk about it in English?
そんなに　たまってるんならそれを　英会話で
披露してみれば　いいんじゃない？
English is all about feeling, so with that much passion grammar is secondary.
英語なんて　気の持ちようなんだから
それぐらい　強いパッションがあれば
文法なんて　二の次よ
"OZ News Episode 1"
And thus my OZ News became a well-known event in the English conversation circle.
そうして　それは　「ＯＺニュース」として
英会話サークルの　名物コーナーになっていった
Ｈｏｗ’ｓ　ＯＺ　ｔｏｄａｙ？
イエ　アー
OZ news is going great, don't you think?
「ＯＺニュース」絶好調ね
羽貫さんのおかげですよ
小津の悪事は　ワールドワイドだ
It's all thanks to you, Hanuki-san.
Ozu's evil deeds know no cultural boundaries.
Around this time Hanuki-san and I would always go to a cafe after the circle meeting.
そのころには　わたしは　羽貫さんと　サークルの後
毎回　カフェで　お茶をするようになっていた
Hanuki-san, do you drink?
羽貫さん　お酒は？
I don't mind it.
嫌いじゃないんだけどね…
迷惑　掛けるから　親しい人としか　飲まないの
It can cause problems, though, so I only drink with people I'm close to.
Close to?
親しい人…
げーっ！？
What's the matter?
どうしたんですか？
キモーい！　窪塚よ
Eww! It's Kubouzuka!
"From: Kubouzuka
I'm in the hotel lounge right now.
Want to come for a drink? (´∀`)ノ★"
I guess those speeches weren't all exaggeration.
あの　スピーチは　あながち　誇張ではないんですね
Hell no. That perverted dentist has a wife and kids, and he's still doing this every day!
やんなっちゃう　あの　セクハラ歯科医
妻子がいるにも　かかわらず　毎日　これよ
Every day?
毎日！？
Maybe I should quit and sue his ass!
いっそ訴えて　辞めてやろうかしら
Thanks.
Don't worry, I'll handle it.
Hanuki-san, do you have a boyfriend?
羽貫さんは　恋人とかいるんですか？
うーん　付き合ってんだか　付き合ってないんだか…
Whether we're going out or not...
It's a love hate relationship.
まあ　腐れ縁だよねー
What's he like?
どんな　感じの人なんですか？
Like this.
こんなの
But he's been totally neglecting me,
でも　ずっと　ほったらかされてるし
so if it's like this, maybe I'd rather have some guy that asks me out every day.
こうやって　キモくても
毎日　誘ってくれる男の方が　いいのかもね
そういう　君は？
And you?
Uh, I'm always being dragged around by Ozu, so...
いやあ　いつも　小津に
付きまとわれていて　なかなか
Oh yeah? I hear you've been exchanging letters.
あら　そう？
文通してるとかって　聞いたけど？
うわあ　文通は　ただの趣味です
That's just a hobby!
キャンパスライフの　隠し味　程度のことで
It's not like I'm trying to add some extra flavor to my campus life or something!
そんなんじゃありません
小津のやつ　そんなことまで　言ってるんですか？
Did Ozu really tell you all that?
That evil bastard...
悪魔め！
とはいえ　小津君も　あれで
純粋なところあるでしょ？
Well, Ozu can be very devoted as well.
見当たりませんな
Doesn't seem that way to me.
There you go again.
またまた
小津君の恋の話　聞いてないの？
You haven't heard about Ozu-kun's love?
えっ　えっ　えっ？
His love?
あいつの恋？
Ozu-kun is in love with someone right now.
小津君　今　恋愛中よ
His partner has led a sheltered life, so he's having quite a lot of trouble.
相手は　箱入りのお嬢さまで
小津君　結構　苦労してるみたい
内緒にしてくれって　言われてるけど
He told me to keep it a secret, though.
For someone like him? No way in the world!
あいつにかぎって　そんなわけありません！
Oh, sorry. Going to a "mystery hotpot."
あっ　ごめん　これから　闇鍋なんだ
With "him."
これたちと　また
Later.
ただいま
I'm home.
So, dear viewers, be not surprised!
視聴者諸君　驚くなかれ
わたしは　ひょんなことから　ここ数週間
I have been living these past few weeks with
this woman, Kaori-san, after some happenings.
この香織さんという女性と　同棲しているのだ
Those of you who see a love-doll as nothing more
ラブドールを性欲処理の道具にしか
見ていない　やからには　分からないだろうが
than a device to manage one's sexual desires will not understand,
but this is extremely sophisticated taste.
これは　高尚な趣味である
Pardon me.
ちょっと失礼
"Aiming to become an international actor.
Vacation Abroad (Europe, America)
Study Acting Abroad"
"Today I taught English conversation again."
「今日も英会話を教えてきました」
"Although the longest I've studied abroad is in Paris,
「留学経験は　パリの方が長いのですが
わたしの経験も　留学をしたことのない
みんなには　重宝されているようです」
my experience is of great value to everyone who has not."
And furthermore, I had been exchanging letters
さらに　わたしは　この２年間　あるきっかけから
with a girl after a certain point for these past two years.
一人の女性と　文通を続けているのである
Her name is Higuchi Keiko-san,
相手の名前は　樋口　景子さんといい
文面から　知性と教養が　におい立つ
わたしの理想像というべき　女性である
and I can tell her intelligence and education from her letters.
She is surely my ideal woman.
大学に入学するまでは　身辺が
華やいだことは　まるでなかった
Nothing much remarkable had happened to me prior to entering college.
And once I realized that, I found myself on the board of the game of "Love."
それが　どうしたことか　今　気が付けば
恋愛すごろくの盤上にいる
From now on I must continuously meet women,
これからは　女性との出会いが　引きも切らず
keep meticulous dates in my date book,
"Take a walk together.
Eat mitarashi dango at entrance to Shimogamo Shrine.
Start to talk about moving in."
予定帳には　あいびきの予定が　みっちり
のどから血が出るほど
むつ言を　語らなければならないだろう
and whisper sweet nothings until I start coughing up blood, yes?
"Go to Kyoto zoo on a weekend date.
Lots of families with children,
start thinking about marriage."
Just thinking about it made me dizzy...
考えるだけで　うんざりする
I had to choose one eventually.
いつかは　一人に　決めなければならない
But I was also happy as I was pondering it.
そう思いながらも　わたしは　幸せだった
However, the situation took a sudden turn!
しかし　事態は　急転直下を迎えた
It may look like I was turning things around well,
順調に回っているかに見えた　わたしの歯車が
but everything started suddenly going out-of-gear!
にわかに狂いを見せ始めた
Ｉ　ｃａｍｅ　ｈｅｒｅ　ａｆｔｅｒ　ｗｏｒｋｉｎｇ　ａｔ　ａ　ｄｅｎｔｉｓｔ．
This is odd. Something is wrong.
おかしい…　何が　おかしいんだ？
Her grammar! Her grammar is quite accurate!
文法だ　文法が　やけに整っている
What's the matter? What happened to her soulful speech overflowing with passion?
どうしたのだ　あふれ出る感情は　余すところなく表現しきる
ソウルフルなスピーチは　どこへいったのだ
Ｇｏ　ｔｏ　ｈｅｌｌ，　ＯＺ！
Hey, wanna go out for some drinks?
どう？　今日は飲みに行かない？
I was finally asked out for a drink by Hanuki-san!
とうとう　羽貫さんから　飲みに誘われた
親しい間柄という　お墨付きを　もらったということだ
This certifies that she feels close to me now!
えっと…
Um...
I have a report I need to write today...
今日は　ちょっと　リポートがあるので
Oh, I see.
そっか…
Right. Good luck on your report!
うん　リポート頑張ってね
Is this okay?
いいのか？　よかったのか？
You sure about this?
あのまま　羽貫さんを行かせて
Letting Hanuki-san go like that?
Hanuki-san was clearly not acting like herself today.
今日の羽貫さんは　明らかに様子が変だった
But he's been totally neglecting me...
でも　ずっと　ほったらかされてるし
Perhaps something happened between her and her boyfriend?
恋人と何か　あったのかもしれない
だからこそ　わたしを　飲みに誘ってくれたのだ
That would explain why she asked me out for drinks.
Perhaps Hanuki-san needed some emotional support?
羽貫さんは　心のよりどころが　欲しかったのではないか？
２年来のお茶飲み友達として　わたしが
Should not I, her café buddy of two years, provide support in her time of need?
支えてあげるべきでは　なかったか
But today is my last day with Kaori-san.
しかし　今日は　香織さんの最後の日でもある
We are being torn apart.
わたしたちは　引きはがされてしまうのだ
I wonder if you'll forget about me?
わたしのことを　忘れてしまうかな？
And also, I received this letter from Keiko-san the other day.
それに　もう一人
景子さんからも　先日
ついに　こんな手紙が届いた
I can wait no longer. I want to tell you.
「もう待てません　はっきりさせたいです」
I'll be waiting at the Cafe Collection.
「カフェコレクションにて　お待ちしております」
If perchance you do not come, let us no longer persist in this exchange of letters.
「もし　来られなかったときは
今後　一切の手紙のやりとりを　終わりにしましょう」
She is waiting tonight as well.
この待ち合わせも　今夜なのだ
All my accounts from these past two years are approaching settlement!
これまでの　２年間の　総決算が迫られている
I see.
なるほど
Before I realized it, I had come to the fortune teller in Kiyamachi.
気が付くと　わたしは　木屋町の占い師の店に来ていた
You are currently having difficulty choosing between three things,
あなたは　今　３つのものに目移りをし
悩んでおられますが
いずれにせよ　好機は目の前に　ぶら下がっておりますぞ
but opportunity is always dangling before your eyes.
That'll be 6,000 yen.
はい　６，０００円
You didn't answer a thing!
何も　答えが出ていません！
So if it's like this, I'd rather have some guy that asks me out every day.
こうやって　キモくても　毎日
誘ってくれる男の方が　いいのかもね
I knew it, I can't leave her be!
やはり　放っておけない
今日の彼女だったら
あのエロ歯科医の誘いにも　没落しかねない
I cannot allow her to be ruined tonight by some perverted dentist's invitation!
まずは　羽貫さんだ
First comes Hanuki-san!
Hanuki-san, don't let yourself fall into Kubouzuka's clutches!
羽貫さん！　窪塚の毒牙にかかっては　いかん！
Y-You? Why aren't you at your post?
なっ　何だ　お前！　持ち場は　どうした？
城ヶ崎さん！？
Jougasaki-san?
And you! Why are you here?
あんたこそ　なぜ　こんなところに！
あれ？　２人とも知り合いなんだ？
Oh? You two know each other?
I don't really understand, though...
何だか　よく分からないけど
Wow, look at you go!
君　いけるね！
I have high tolerance.
安全パイですが
I figured you'd be worthless at your job.
やはり　仕事も半人前だな
Oh! Is it time for a drinking contest?
おお～　飲み比べモードね
飲もう　飲もう
Drink, drink!
君に　このワインの味は　分かるかな？
I wonder if you can appreciate the taste of this wine?
And how many bottles will it take for you?
何本飲めば分かりますか？
よっ！　いけいけ！
Yeah! Go, go!
君が　そのつもりなら　受けて立とう！
If that's how you want to play it!
先に　つぶれた方が負けです
First one to collapse loses!
That goes without saying.
言うまでもない
Well I'm not giving in!
しかし　意地でも　わたしは！
I won't fall!
つぶれない！
Shall we move on to "Walker"?
ウオツカでも　いくかい？
Sounds good to me.
いいですね　ご一緒します
Count me in!
じゃあ　わたしも
It was a grand, manly battle between Jougasaki and I.
わたしと　城ヶ崎氏の　男のメンツを懸けた大勝負
I was starting to lose consciousness...
意識が　もうろうとしてくる
But Jougasaki also seemed close to losing.
しかし　城ヶ崎氏も　相当　参っているようだ
By the way, Hanuki-san showed no signs of being done in by the alcohol.
ところで　羽貫さんは　一向に酔いつぶれる気配がない
Let's drink more!
もっと　飲め～！
I was already at my limit.
わたしは　もうすでに　限界である
That's it, I'm...
もう　駄目か…　うう…
I-I won!
かっ　勝った
Hanuki-san, don't fall for a man like Jougasaki!
羽貫さん　城ヶ崎のような男に
陥落してはいけません！
もっと　自分を大事に…
Have higher standards!
Oh, Jougasaki-kun and I aren't like that.
あら　城ヶ崎君は　そんなんじゃないわよ
He's just an old friend.
昔からの友達なの
But I didn't think you'd come.
だけど　来てくれるとは　思わなかったわ
Let's head to another place!
もう１軒　行こう！　えっ！？
You still want to drink?
まだ　飲むんですか？
I've got to finish that report and...
そろそろ　リポートが…
Did you say something?
えーっ　何か言った？
Come on, let's go home already...
いいかげん　帰りましょうよ
I can't hear you!
聞こえなーい
If I don't hurry, Kaori-san will...
早くしないと　香織さんが…
You jerk!
バッキャロー！　どこへでも　行っちまえ！
Go to hell and die!
"Shimogamo Taxi"
Hanuki-san, your address!
羽貫さん　住所！
Sakyou-ku Shimogamohigashi...
左京区　下鴨東…
I've got a Castella, so spend the night...
カステラ　やるから　添い寝して
I have to hurry, or Keiko-san will...
いやっ　早くしないと　景子さんが…
Please, try and walk straight!
ちゃんと歩いてください
ちょっと　くすぐったい
Hey, that tickles!
This is lookin' good!
いい流れだぜ！
What's your room number?
部屋　何番です？
忘れた
I forget.
Come on, now...
しっかりしてください
Just kiddin'...
冗談　冗談
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I wanna check my mail!
あ～　ポスト見る
I think that can wait, don't you?
今　見なくてもいいでしょ
ヘイ　ヘイ　行けるぜ
Hey, hey, that's what I'm talkin' about!
Here we go, here we go, here we go!
きたぜ　きたぜ　きたぜ
やっほー！　やっときた！
Finally!
My once-in-a-lifetime chance!
千載一遇の大チャンスだー！
Ever since I passed through that accursed gate of puberty,
呪われた　思春期の門を　くぐって　この方
わが　ジョニーには　惨めな思いを強いてきた
my Johnny has been forced into a miserable state.
Indeed my history is nothing but the history of my Johnny's suppression.
わたしの歴史は　虐げられてきたジョニーの歴史
そのものだ
For having a man like me as your master... I apologize!
わたしのような男を　主人に持ったばっかりに　すまぬ
Tonight's the night!
今夜　決めようぜ！
しかし！
However!
I will keep my pride as a civilized person!
わたしは　あくまで　文明人としての誇りを保つ！
What?!
何をー！？
Where is your key?
鍵は　どこです？
Uh... Uh... Huh?
あれ？
There it is...
あっ　あった
Oh? It won't go in...
あれ？　入らない
Man...
あん　もう…
Ah, it went in.
あっ　入った
Want to come in for some herb tea?
ハーブティー　飲んでいかない？
Well, I...
いやっ　わたしは…
...don't mind if I do!
喜んでー！
Sorry, I think I drank too much.
ごめんね　ちょっと飲み過ぎた
川のそばで　いいでしょ　ちょっと　うるさいけど
It's nice facing the river.
Kind of loud, though.
"Inside the Brain"
How are we supposed to get through this situation in a chivalrous manner?
いかにして　この局面を　紳士的に切り抜けるか
We must retain our honor!
体面を保つのだ！
Here we go! Yeehaw!
いけるぜ！　いっちゃえ！
Have a seat on the sofa.
ソファに座ってて
Wait until it boils.
ちょっと沸くまで
Let me read your palm.
手相　見せて　う～ん
Oh, this one's totally separated.
あっ　完全に　ここ離れてる
That means you can't tell the situation you're in.
空気　読めないラインだって
でも　恋愛には向いてるらしいよ
But it seems like you're suited to romance.
きたぞー！
Here it comes! Get this party started, heck yeah!
がばっといけ　がばっと！
Hey, let me see inside your mouth.
ねえ　口の中　見せて
Wait, Hanuki-san...
いや　ちょっと　羽貫さん
I'll give you a gum massage.
歯茎　マッサージしてあげよっか
This one's on the house.
しかも　タダで
What's the matter?
Why do you look so scared?
どうしたの？　怖い顔して
I-I always look like this!
もともと　こういう顔ですから
You liar...
嘘つき
さっきは　そんな所に
しわは　なかったでございますよ
You didn't have a wrinkle there before.
See?
ほれほれ
Silence!
静粛に！
"Frontal Lobe"
Amygdala, situation report!
扁桃体　現在の状況を報告しろ
Yes. Currently our pulse is elevated, and sweating will not cease.
"Amygdala"
はい
現在　心拍　脈拍　共に上昇
発汗も止まりません
The cause is from here.
"Mothership"
"Emergency"
"External Vessel of Primary Factor"
"Primary Factor"
原因は　ここ
Two soft swells are pressing against the mothership.
柔らかい２つの膨らみが　母体に押し付けられています
"Cerebellum"
"Parietal Lobe"
I tried to fend off such a situation calmly,
わたしは　この事態を　冷静に受け止めようとしたが
"Occipital Lobe"
"Temporal Lobe"
おおかたの予想どおり　それは　困難を極めた
but as I'd suspected, it was an extremely difficult task.
"Frontal Lobe"
Why is it that these soft swellings of no merit have such control over us men?
なぜ　あんなに　ふっくらしている　ぐらいしか
取りえのないものに　われわれ　男が支配されているのか
I was not able to solve that riddle.
その謎は解けていなかった
ご託は　いい！
Stop being so pretentious!
Don't think, tool!
Ｄｏｎ’ｔ　ｔｈｉｎｋ！　Ｆｅｅｌ！
Of course, considering the position
Hanuki-san's breasts are in right now,
むろん　現今における　羽貫さんの乳との位置関係上
わたしも　興奮するに　やぶさかでないが
I would not fault myself for becoming aroused...
We're aroused?!
興奮したのか！？
What happened to our pride?
誇りはないのか！
とはいえ　このような単純な膨らみに
純粋なハートを　わしづかみにされて
So I cannot allow these mere swells to grab hold of my pure heart
長年　守ることを　余儀なくされてきた純潔を
棒に振るわけにはいかない！
and sacrifice my long-protected, unavoidable chastity!
My pride won't allow it!
わたしの誇りが許さない！
Don't be so tense.
力　抜いて
See, they're all worn down.
ほら　すり減ってる
All you ever do is grind your teeth.
You're so tense...
歯ぎしりばっかりしてるでしょ
ずいぶん　力　入ってる
It's my turn!
ヒャッホー！　出番だ！
Your gums are soft, though.
歯茎は柔らかいのね
They're all pink and inexperienced.
ピンク色で　うぶみたいだわ
Doesn't it feel good right here?
ここ　気持ちいいでしょ
You want me to go deeper?
もっと奥がいいの？　あが…
"Succum"
Take emergency shelter in the bathroom!
トイレに　緊急避難してください！
Over there!
"Bathroom"
"Ah, it's a cockroach!"
Ah, it's a cockroach!
あっ　ゴキブリが！！
This was our opportunity! Open up!
今こそ　好機じゃねえか！　開けろ！
I can't.
駄目だ！
Whatever, open up!
いいから　開けろ！
I can't!
駄目だ！
Can I be called civilized if I allow myself to be controlled by my desires of the hour?
一時の欲望に押し流されて　文明人といえるか
Can I keep my pride taking advantage of a woman falling over from too much alcohol?
女性が　酒で　ふわふわしているのに
乗じて　誇りが保てるか
Open up!
開けて！
This situation came about unexpectedly,
思いがけず　このような状況に　なってしまったが
わたしは　いま一度　努めて冷静に考えてみた
so it was only now that I tried to think it through calmly.
Hanuki-san, Kaori-san, or Keiko-san?
羽貫さんか　香織さんか　景子さんか
The choice is obvious, you dolt!
迷うことなんてねえだろー！
It was then that I thought of something.
そのとき　わたしは　あることに思い至った
Could it be that Hanuki-san actually wanted to be with me?
羽貫さんの　好きな相手というのは
実は　わたしのことではないか
Didn't you say it?
あなた　言ってたじゃないですか
It's inexcusable to partner with someone you don't have a burning passion for
"Last Summer"
身を焦がすほど　好きでもない相手と
寂しいが故に　欲求から相手を求めるなど
based purely on desire just because you're lonely!
言語道断！
But, why?!
何でだ！
I despise this sort of thing.
わたしは　それを憎んできた
The door to a new world is opening!
新しい世界が開けるぜ！
Don't you want to see what's on the other side?
向こうを見てみたいとは　思わないのか！
Yes, I want to see! But now is not the time!
見てはみたいが　今は　まだ　そのときではない！
If this isn't the opportunity, then when is?
今が好機でなくて　いつが好機なんだ！
It's because this is an opportunity that I should wait for her to sober up
好機なればこそ　彼女が
しらふに戻るのを待ってから
before properly restarting merger negotiations!
正当な手段で合併交渉を　再開すべきであろう！
お願いだ！
I'm begging you!
俺は　今まで　ずっと不遇を囲ってきたんだ！
I've always been complaining about my bad luck!
I can't take it anymore!
もう　飽きるほど　我慢してきたんだよ！
Johnny, I can't...
ジョニー　駄目なんだ
The bonds between man and woman can't be tied so simply...
男女の仲というものは
そんな簡単に結ばれちゃ　駄目なんだ
I know... I know!
分かった　分かったよ！
Don't mind me!
俺は　平気さ！
I'll just have to wait some more.
いまさら　ちょっとくらい　待ちが増えたって
どうってことねえよ
What's a little while longer?
Johnny, you understand me?
ジョニー　分かってくれたか
I wonder how much time had passed?
どのくらい　時間がたったことだろう
When I came to, it seemed like I had fallen asleep.
気が付くと　わたしは　眠っていたようである
Has Hanuki-san calmed down by now?
羽貫さんは　もう　落ち着いたであろうか
For some reason, Hanuki-san looks strangely like Ozu.
目の前にいる羽貫さんは　何だか　小津のようである
というか　小津である
Oh wait, that is Ozu.
What are you doing?
何してまんの？
Try putting yourself in my shoes, being called out by Hanuki-san or Jougasaki-san.
楽しい時間に　羽貫さんや　城ヶ崎さんに
呼び出された　僕の身にもなってください
But, why?
だから　どうして
彼女は　酒を飲み過ぎると
理性のたがが緩むというか
When she drinks, the wheels come off her reason a bit, you see.
そういうことで
何だ　それは
What's that supposed to mean?
Did she, perhaps, lick your face?
ひょっとして　顔を　なめられませんでした？
Yeah...
She has a bad habit of licking people's faces when she drinks.
彼女　飲むと　人の顔を　なめる癖があって
She refrains from going drinking with people she doesn't know well.
付き合いの浅い人とは　飲むの　控えてたんですが
But today she got carried away.
今日は　ちょいと　度が過ぎた　ということで
In other words, she'd like you to consider what happened today as water under the bridge.
つまり　今日　起こったことは　水に流してほしいと
何と…
That's...
あなた　何もしなかったんでしょうな？
You didn't do anything, right?
顔を　なめられただけだ
All I did was get my face licked.
Considering your looks, that's all you could expect.
まっ　あなたの器量なら
どうせ　そんなとこでしょうけど
While you shut yourself up in the bathroom,
あなたが　閉じこもってんで
Hanuki-san is hugging the toilet at the convenience store getting her comeuppance.
羽貫さんは　今　コンビニの便器を
抱え込んで　報いを受けています
By the way, Ozu, don't tell me that you and Hanuki-san...
ところで　小津　まさか　お前が羽貫さんと！
恐ろしいこと　言わないでください
Please, don't even joke about that.
She requires a person like the Master far more than an ordinary individual such as myself.
わたしみたいな　凡人には
あんな人など　とても　とても
それこそ　師匠のような人でないと
And yet, for some reason, I felt slightly relieved.
しかし　わたしは　なぜか　少し　ほっとした
"I collected Kaori-san. The Castella is a reward from Jougasaki-san. -Ozu"
I wonder how long Keiko-san had waited?
景子さんは　何時まで　待っていたであろうか
But, it's for the best. I have maintained my hard-protected chastity.
しかし　よかった　わたしは\辛うじて　貞操を守り通した
男と女が　靴ひものように　結ばれて　たまるか
You think I'll let myself be tied to a woman like some shoelace?
I've just returned to the starting point of the game of "Love."
何の　恋愛すごろくの振り出しに戻っただけではないか
This kind of thing's an everyday occurrence.
そんなことは　日常茶飯事である
I got a Castella out of it, so I think it turned out pretty good, all things considered.
カステラが手に入っただけでも
割の良い話だと思え
Hang in there! Keep hanging in there!
我慢しろ　これで　我慢しろ！
But, I wouldn't mind if I could live my life again, even just a little bit!
だあ…　しかし！　もう一度　人生を
やり直せと言われれば　やり直すことは
At the very least, starting from a few hours ago!
いささかも　やぶさかでない！　せめて　数時間前からでも！
tengoku iku tame mainichi kosotto
天国　いくため　毎日こそっと
In order to go to heaven. Everyday, I quietly
naishou de ii koto shiteta kedo
内緒で　いいこと　してたけど
and privately do good deeds
namida hitohira
涙ひとひら
But a single teardrop
atama kurakura
あたまくらくら
Sends my head spinning
ano ko hasuppa koi dorobou
あの娘　はすっぱ　恋泥棒
That stupid girl, that love thief
watashi kenage ii hito
わたしけなげ　いいひと
I am a good and pure person
kanawanakatta koigokoro
叶わなかった恋心
My longing heart was not fulfilled
kamisama doushite
神様どうして
Why, god?
yurusanakucha koi dorobou
ゆるさなくっちゃ恋泥棒
I must forgive her. That love thief
ano ko tabun ii hito
あの娘たぶん　いいひと
Maybe she was actually a good person
wasurenakucha konna koto
忘れなくっちゃこんなこと
I have to forget all these things
watashi wa tengoku
わたしは天国
I'm in heaven
yurusanakucha
ゆるさなくっちゃ
I have to forgive her!